### RESUME PHILIP W. STEPHENSON

275 Union Boulevard 905 St. Louis, MO 63108 636-675-1379 (Mobile), Skype - philstepson phil@phil-stephenson.com

#### SUMMARY

Experienced Product Manager, Business Development Manager with a demonstrated ability to manage, enable and promote the sale of software, hardware and enterprise systems with an emphasis on solution sales focused on enhancing revenues.

Oracle Core Database Exadata/Database Machine Oracle Database Appliance Business Development Technical Pre-sales Strategic Partner Development Product Management Product Strategies Competitive Analysis

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ORACLE CORPORATION. Redwood Shores, CA, October 1998 - Present -

Senior Principal Product Manager (Director), Oracle Database Appliance, Server Technologies – Responsible for Strategic Partner development and outbound activities.

- Managing our Strategic global VAD/VAR partners to create a knowledge infrastructure and skills for hardware/software solutions sales
  for the Oracle Database Appliance, including ISV turnkey solutions using OVM, traditional hardware replacements, migrations and
  workload consolidations. Acting as a product evangelist and as an outbound product manager for our partner channel and Oracle
  Direct sales teams.
- Shifted traditional Sun Partner business from hardware only to solutions sales model that included software. Established a pipeline for partners for the Oracle Database Appliance Engineered System including storage and enterprise software licenses.
- Established solution blueprints for systems integrators for virtual machine 'In-a-Box' solutions to enhance partner revenues with ISV and red-stack turn key solutions.

Senior Principal Product Manager, Oracle Exadata Database Machine, Server Technologies – Responsible for outbound product management activities and release management.

- Release managed the internal process to release, maintain, roll out and announce Exadata Database Machine from V1 through X2-8.
- Assisted Oracle Marketing to plan product announcements, write and staff product demos, and supported sales teams to achieve their
  revenue goals by assisting in the development of marketing assets. Primary contact for field sales preparing go to market training and
  collateral and internal sales readiness.
- Delivered speaking and presentation engagements of Oracle technologies at Oracle user's group meetings, trade shows, the Oracle Executive Briefing Center, Oracle OpenWorld and at customer sites. Founding Oracle Advisor to establish the IOUG Exadata Special Interest Group to promote greater customer adoption and acceptance of Oracle's Exadata Database Machine products.
- Our product roll out resulted in exceptional sales activity growing sales revenues from \$30M to over \$500M in two just years.

### <u>Group Manager Product Management, Database Lite, Server Technologies</u> – Managed Product Management team for Oracle's Database Lite product.

- Created product specifications and roadmap for future product releases and responsible for product release management including Beta programs. Evaluated product requirements and requests for product enhancements from internal and external requestors including customers, ISV and SI partners.
- · Compile market and competitive product research as input to existing and future product planning.
- Responsible for producing all product collateral including internal and external presentations, White Papers, sample code, external and
  internal website content. Prepare and participate in industry trade shows including OracleWorld, CTIA, GSM-World, Embedded
  Systems, Customer Advisory Board meetings and all internal and external product training.
- Development liaison to Business Development, Marketing, Analyst Relations field marketing, ISV and SI partners worldwide.

# <u>Director of Business Development. Oracle Wireless and Voice Division</u> – Manage Global team that provided sales support to Oracle's large and critical accounts in North and South America.

- Coordinate the assembly of necessary resources to professionally respond to potential new business opportunities and orchestrate
  development of new strategies to address existing and emerging markets.
- Proactively communicate benefits of Oracle Wireless and Voice products and services to new and incumbent accounts, Systems Integrators, ISVs, partners and Oracle field account teams.
- Identify customer needs and requirements to create effective product enhancements and platform extensions for Oracle's Wireless and Voice products and services
- Investigate and report on new markets for Oracle Wireless and Voice products and services maintaining a strong working relationship with Product Management, Product Development and Marketing in preparing sales collateral, and education for sales teams and partners.

## RESUME PHILIP W. STEPHENSON

- Provided technical marketing and support of Oracle's complete Information Management Solution including database servers, application servers, application development tools, (Designer, Developer, JDeveloper, WebDB), and Business Intelligence System tools for decision support, data warehousing, and OLAP, (Discoverer, Reports and Express).
- Developed and managed relationships with Oracle's third party hardware and software partners and Systems Integrators.
- Q2 software license sales of \$3.4 million, opened 5 new Major Accounts whose annual sales revenue was over \$500 million, and my team finished 1999 year with \$6.3 million in sales for a guota attainment of 107%

### <u>SEQUENT COMPUTER SYSTEMS, INC.</u>, St. Louis, MO 1998 – October 1998, <u>Senior Systems Analyst</u> - Primary mission was technical marketing Sequent's Intel based servers to the Boeing enterprise in St. Louis.

- Focus was technical pre-sales of Sequent's Decision Support Solutions including hardware, software and consulting services with an emphasis on quantifying business benefits.
- Targeted Boeing's Aircraft and Missiles Company providing hardware and consulting solutions for Financial and manufacturing systems.

### <u>EMC CORPORATION.</u> St. Louis, MO 1995 – 1998, <u>Senior Systems Engineer</u> - Primary mission was marketing to new and emerging accounts, selling EMC's Enterprise Storage hardware and software in Mid-West Sales Territory.

- Primary focus was supporting the sale and successful implementation of EMC's enterprise storage software and articulating business benefits of EMC software solutions.
- Developed twenty-two new accounts resulting in the installation of multiple terabytes of SCSI and channel attached storage.
- Provided technical marketing assistance to business partners Systems Integrators and storage resellers to promote the sale of storage hardware and software.
- Promoted development of follow on business by supplying installed accounts with Systems Engineering support for systems architecture design, performance evaluation and capacity planning.

# <u>AMDAHL CORPORATION.</u> (Midwest Region), St. Louis, MO 1990 –1995, <u>Account Executive Open Enterprise Systems</u> - Territory included St. Louis and Kansas City responsible for selling Amdahl open system products including Sun, Cray SuperServer, Open Software, Clariion storage and professional services.

- Successfully sold \$1.5M of Sun servers, Clariion storage and professional services engagements.
- Sun VAR certified and trained on Sun servers and storage.

#### Senior Marketing Systems Engineer, Open Systems - Currently provide marketing and technical support for open system products, specializing in Sun products and services, large system UNIX and SCSI attached storage subsystems.

- Provided technical consulting for the porting of a large telephone provisioning system application to mainframe UNIX to promote the marketing of software and processors.
- Project Manager for the implementation of a UNIX based toll recovery accounting system for Southwestern Bell Corporation resulting in processor upgrades.
- Managed data center consolidation project for McDonnell Douglas Aerospace and Information Systems Company resulting in the sale of two large processors.
- Performed a system performance evaluation and capacity planning effort at Ralston Purina Company that resulted in the sale of a processor and storage subsystems.

# <u>ERNST & YOUNG.</u> (Information Technology Consulting), St. Louis, MO 1989 – 1990, <u>Senior Manager</u> - <u>Member of executive staff</u> responsible for the development, delivery, and project management of client consulting services in the Information Technology Consulting Practice.

- Developed engagement and managed a large project for the operating system conversion of Magna Bank Corporation resulting in significant consulting revenues.
- Developed engagement and delivered consulting for hardware acquisition strategy for the Baldor Electric Company, that resulted in significant cost savings.
- Technical project manager for a data center assessment project for McDonnell Douglas Missiles Company that resulted in follow on engagements and significant engagement revenue.

## <u>AMDAHL CORPORATION.</u> (South-Central Marketing Region), Atlanta, GA 1988 – 1989, <u>Regional Systems Engineer</u> - Responsible for technical marketing of processors, storage subsystems, and communications processors.

- Supported metropolitan accounts and successfully sold processors and storage subsystems to Bell South Information Services.
- Responsible for technical pre-sales support to Atlanta fortune 500 accounts.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Science**, <u>University of Tennessee</u>, Business Administration, Economics major and Computer Science minor. **Masters of Science**, Webster University, Computer Science with an emphasis on OO analysis/design and relational database.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Author of *Oracle9i Mobile*, McGraw-Hill Osborne Media, (Oracle Press), and ISBN: 007222455X